<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ashwani Khemani on Ashwani Khemani</title>
    <link>https://bhavesh00.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ashwani Khemani on Ashwani Khemani</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Every Breath You Take !!</title>
      <link>https://bhavesh00.github.io/post/evlproject2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 13:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhavesh00.github.io/post/evlproject2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bhavesh00.github.io/img/evlProject2.png&#34; alt=&#34;(Every Breathe You Take)&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the second project for the CS 424 Visualization and Visual Analytics class at UIC. It consists in various visualizations and interactive plots in a web application created using the Shiny library for R. The visualizations are about the Air Quality dataset by County in the United States and Italy, concentrating on the yearly, daily and hourly data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can access the application from &lt;a href=&#34;http://shiny.evl.uic.edu:3838/g4/EveryBreathYouTake/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can learn more about the application &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirkomantovani.com/projects/EveryBreathYouTake.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code for the application is available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mirkomantovani/VisualAnalytics-EveryBreathYouTake&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An short video demonstration of the application is available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UCvc0h6yKMg&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;youtube&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Every Breath You Take !!</title>
      <link>https://bhavesh00.github.io/project/evlproject2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 13:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhavesh00.github.io/project/evlproject2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bhavesh00.github.io/img/evlProject2.png&#34; alt=&#34;(Every Breathe You Take)&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the second project for the CS 424 Visualization and Visual Analytics class at UIC. It consists in various visualizations and interactive plots in a web application created using the Shiny library for R. The visualizations are about the Air Quality dataset by County in the United States and Italy, concentrating on the yearly, daily and hourly data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can access the application from &lt;a href=&#34;http://shiny.evl.uic.edu:3838/g4/EveryBreathYouTake/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can learn more about the application &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirkomantovani.com/projects/EveryBreathYouTake.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code for the application is available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mirkomantovani/VisualAnalytics-EveryBreathYouTake&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An short video demonstration of the application is available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UCvc0h6yKMg&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;youtube&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just Breathe Group - Interesting Things !!</title>
      <link>https://bhavesh00.github.io/post/project1group/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 17:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhavesh00.github.io/post/project1group/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bhavesh00.github.io/img/newPhoto.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;(Group Image)&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Group:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ashwani Khemani&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Abhishek Vasudevan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Varsha Jayaraman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abhishek solution:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The UI is easy to navigate and it&amp;rsquo;s easy to follow things on the screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The colors are pleasing and they work for the color blind people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The different charts had error messages for the case when no data was found for given user input.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ashwani solution:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The overall work done by him was good. He has organized the different visualizations properly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The pie charts created for the AQI were visually appealing and the labeling of the charts was done in a correct manner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Varsha solution:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The way she made use different colors and the display was very pleasant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The comparisons for more than one county was done in a unique way which makes the comparisons more intuitive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All the charts and tables have good color and proper labeling and make it easier for the user to analyze the information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just Breathe !!</title>
      <link>https://bhavesh00.github.io/project/evlproject1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 19:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhavesh00.github.io/project/evlproject1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This page contains the link to the visualization solution optimized for the EVL classroom wall and a description of how to use the application and the things that can be done with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://askheman.shinyapps.io/project1/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Project Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ztN_4RWBkNI&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Youtube Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To use this application follow the following steps :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The home page consists of a shiny dashboard with a side menu to choose what type of visualization user wants to see.
The side menu has two options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One County - visualization consisting of one county.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiple County - visualization consisting of more than one county&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One the user select a side menu option, the corresponding page for the visualization loads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One County:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this page, there are three input options for the user to select.
The user has to select one of the available options in the drop down menu in a sequential order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;State&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;County&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user will then be able to see the different visualization on the screen below by navigating the
different tabs provided in the panels below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first panel has three visualizations for the Air Quality of the state,county and year selected by the user:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pie chart showing the percentage of days where the AQI could be good / moderate / unhealthy for sensitive / unhealthy / very unhealthy / hazardous&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a bar chart showing the number of days where the AQI could be good / moderate / unhealthy for sensitive / unhealthy / very unhealthy / hazardous&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;table showing the number of days where the AQI could be good / moderate / unhealthy for sensitive / unhealthy / very unhealthy / hazardous&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second panel has eight visualizations based on the user input of state , county and year:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;pie chart for each individual pollutant (CO, NO2, Ozone, SO2, PM2.5, PM10 ) showing the percentage of days in the year with that pollutant as the main pollutant (6 charts)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;bar chart showing the number of CO, NO2, Ozone, SO2, PM2.5, PM10 days as the main pollutant&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;table showing the number of CO, NO2, Ozone, SO2, PM2.5, PM10 days as the main pollutant&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third panel has 9 visualizations based on the user input of state , county and year:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a line graph using the annual data from 1980-2018 showing lines for the median, 90th percentile, and max AQI over those years (i.e. the graph should have 3 lines)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a line graph showing the percentages over the years for days CO / days NO2 / days Ozone, days SO2 / days PM2.5 / days pm10 (i.e. the graph should have 6 lines)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6 tables showing the percentages over the years for days CO / days NO2 / days Ozone, days SO2 / days PM2.5 / days pm10&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;location of the chosen county on a pannable and zoomable world map&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a snapshot from the application .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bhavesh00.github.io/img/evlProject1.png&#34; alt=&#34;(Just Breathe)&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just Breathe - Code !!</title>
      <link>https://bhavesh00.github.io/post/evlproject1code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 19:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhavesh00.github.io/post/evlproject1code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The code for the project can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ashwanikhemani/JustBreathe&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The data needed for the project is available in the root folder and the map data is available in the map folder of the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The instructions to run the code:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Online : The project can be run through this &lt;a href=&#34;https://askheman.shinyapps.io/project1/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Offline : To run the project in the local environment , please follow the below instructions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Download the R-language from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.r-project.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;R-website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Download R-Studio free version from this website &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;R-Studio&lt;/a&gt; and then install it
your system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once R-Studio is installed, open the R-Studio using the application file and download the following packages in R-Studio:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;library(shiny)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;library(shinydashboard)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;library(ggplot2)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;library(lubridate)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;library(DT)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;library(jpeg)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;library(grid)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;library(leaflet)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;library(scales)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The packages can be downloaded using the packages menu on the right side in R-Studio home screen. Search the package by name and install the
above packages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once the packages are installed, the user can open the project from source code link provided
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ashwanikhemani/JustBreathe&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;To run the applications, open the app.R and click on Run App button on the upper right side of app.R file screen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The user should now be able to see the various visualization done as part of the Just-Breathe application.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The entire source code has been written using R language and using packages above.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just Breathe - Data!!</title>
      <link>https://bhavesh00.github.io/post/evlproject1data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 19:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhavesh00.github.io/post/evlproject1data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The page contains information about the data used in the Just Breathe project. The data was downloaded from the EPA website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The link to download the data is &lt;a href=&#34;https://aqs.epa.gov/aqsweb/airdata/download_files.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The files for annual summary of data for counties was downloaded from years 1980-2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The files were then extracted and imported using R Studio to create visualization as described in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://ashwanikhemani.github.io/post/evlproject1/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just Breathe --Findings !!</title>
      <link>https://bhavesh00.github.io/post/evlproject1findings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 19:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhavesh00.github.io/post/evlproject1findings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://askheman.shinyapps.io/project1/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Project Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interesting things which were found about the data using the application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The findings are given below for the Cook county of Illinois.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amongst the pollutants, SO2 pollutant has shown a relatively downward trend over the last 25 years with some exceptions in certain years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PM2.5 pollutant has shown a relatively upward trend over the last 25 years with some exceptions in certain years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CO , Carbon monozide emission has been neglible over the last 20 years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These trends show that there has been an effor to reduce harmful emissions but at the same time there are still emissions that need to be controlled to bring them under permissible range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;While comparing different states and their counties, the air Quality in Cook county in Illinois was found to be worse as comapred to those in Florida state.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;States like Nebraska , Utah have comparitively good air quality as compared to states like Illinois, California.
The counties in these states with less population show air quality as expected. The states and the counties which large population
and industry are prone to bad air quality.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The X-Rite Color Challenge and Hue Test !!</title>
      <link>https://bhavesh00.github.io/post/color_test/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 12:54:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhavesh00.github.io/post/color_test/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bhavesh00.github.io/img/color_test.png&#34; alt=&#34;Test Results&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EVL Weather Application !!</title>
      <link>https://bhavesh00.github.io/post/evl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 19:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhavesh00.github.io/post/evl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bhavesh00.github.io/img/evl_2.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;EVL Weather Application&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the link to the website deployed using shinny apps account&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://askheman.shinyapps.io/evlWeatherForR/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;EVL Weather&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weather Updates !!</title>
      <link>https://bhavesh00.github.io/post/weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 19:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhavesh00.github.io/post/weather/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I get my weather updates from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://weather.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;weather channel&lt;/a&gt; !!!
I usually visit weather channel because it provides the most accurate and up to date weather updates.
It shows hourly, daily and weekly weather forecast in an organized manner.
The website and phone application are easy to navigate and to use.
I highly recommend the application to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bhavesh00.github.io/img/weather_channel.png&#34; alt=&#34;Weather image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time for a new beginning !!</title>
      <link>https://bhavesh00.github.io/post/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 20:23:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhavesh00.github.io/post/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few days ago I read the following tweet somewhere on the internet !!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;When you’ve written the same code 3 times, write a function&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;When you’ve given the same in-person advice 3 times, write a blog post&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; David Robinson (@drob) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/drob/status/928447584712253440?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;November 9, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to relate it to my real life experience and it definitely did make a lot of sense. I have seen myself sometimes repeating and sharing the same advice with my friends and colleagues. So, I decided to start my own blog to share my learnings and experiences with everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoy reading and have become an avid reader (I would have been surprised if someone said that about me a couple of years ago).
I love to read about a lot of varied topics and yes anything related to the computers (we go long way back) and the technology. Currently, I am more occupied with reading academic texts and papers about topics of my interests and I would love to share anything I find interesting in them. Apart from reading, I really enjoy sharing my knowledge with people which is the main motivation behind this blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talking to people who are new to the field or are nervous because of the initial experience with something and helping them is something I have always cherished. &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Success is not counted by how high you have climbed but by how many people you brought with you&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/strong&gt;And I try to stand by this each and every day of my life. I do sometimes digress to philosophy even when I try very hard not to, I promise I would avoid it in the future posts :) But, coming back to the purpose of this blog and the interests that I would like to talk about here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I currently find the areas of &lt;em&gt;machine learning and distributed systems&lt;/em&gt; very fascinating. I would love to share my perspective about different concepts and try to make topics in these areas more interesting and understandable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently read an article which talked about &lt;em&gt;deep learning&lt;/em&gt;, I apologize for the jargon. Let&amp;rsquo;s for now not focus on what does it mean as it&amp;rsquo;s not that important at the moment. The article said that the fact that deep learning is hyped is itself hyped. I agree with it as people are trying to make use of buzzwords to gain traction and there is nothing wrong with that. My point is, yes, it may be hyped, but what differentiates a genuine enthusiast and person who wants to make use of any form of science and technology is not how much hype one can create, it&amp;rsquo;s about how much impact one can have with their creation over the world and its population. This is the sole reason behind my curiosity about machine learning and distributed systems. I think they are very useful and if people try to make use of them to solve real-world problems, the opportunities are endless !!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I might sometimes write about some non-technical topics also, but I would try to keep them separate. I have found the internet and online communities very useful for the knowledge I have gained in my life. &lt;strong&gt;This is my way to give something back to it !!&lt;/strong&gt; I hope this blog would be useful for everyone and I would love to hear your comments and feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned !!!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Empirical Investigation into Large-Scale Devops Pipeline programs</title>
      <link>https://bhavesh00.github.io/project/pa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhavesh00.github.io/project/pa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Investigated many Devops pipeline programs and obtained statistical data that describe content and patterns in Devops
pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Java, Jenkins, GitHub&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source Code available &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ashwanikhemani/PipelineAnalyzer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conditional Random Field for optical character recognition (OCR)</title>
      <link>https://bhavesh00.github.io/project/crf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhavesh00.github.io/project/crf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed and developed parallel optimization algorithm based on the LBFGS solver provided by PETSc,
leveraging its parallel primitives and testing the scalability on cluster&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented stochastic gradient solvers (SGD and ADAM), and tested their efficiency in comparison with LBFGS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source Code available &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ashwanikhemani/ConvexOptimization&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevOps Orchestration to simulate end to end DevOps workflow at an enterprise level</title>
      <link>https://bhavesh00.github.io/project/do/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhavesh00.github.io/project/do/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created a DevOps application workflow for automatically building and analyzing software applications statically as part of
the workflow to obtain information about relationships among components of these applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Java, Jenkins, Gitlab, GitHub&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source Code available &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ashwanikhemani/DevOpsOrchester&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instance Segmentation using Convolutional Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://bhavesh00.github.io/project/maskrcnn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhavesh00.github.io/project/maskrcnn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Mask R-CNN (Regional Convolutional Neural Network) can be used in instance
segmentation, and has been quite sucessful when compared with other architectures
for the same task. In this project we look at its performance on two
well known datasets, cityscapes and CSAIL Places, and try to see the impact of
modifying hyperparameters and using different network architectures in the backbone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Summary of the Problem
Instance Segmentation is the combination of three other tasks making it very difficult. Those three
tasks are Image Classification, Object Detection, and Semantic Segmentation. See Figure 1 for an
overview of the task.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Instance Segmentation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Classification, being the most studied of the three, is a task where you are given an image
and the goal is to classify it. Examples of such studies are those done on the MNIST dataset [1].
In MNIST, the task is to classify handwritten digits given only an image of the digit. Some of the
most successful approaches involve CNN architectures, like VGG, GoogleLeNet, ResNet, and many
others.
Object Detection has the same domain, but the goal is to find all instances of an object and find the
smallest bounding box around the object. One way to structure this as a machine learning task is
to formulate it as a Regression problem, where the bounding box is defined by a set of coordinates.
This is done in our Mask R-CNN implementation and its immediate predecessor, Faster R-CNN [2].
The goal of Semantic Segmentation is to classify each pixel, effectively segmenting an image into its
semantic components. This was a difficult task because there was no obvious way to generate predictions
for each pixel, without feeding the whole image multiple times through a traditional CNN
classification network, and this would make the problem intractable. One well known solution to
this is to use a Fully Convolutional Network (FCN), which would have an Encoder/Decoder structure
by first using Convolution Layers and Pooling&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cityscapes&lt;/strong&gt;
Cityscapes has data from street scenes, so an application of a network trained on this dataset is
autonomous vehicles. The dataset has approximately 5,000 examples and 30 classes with fine grain
annotations. We used about 3,500 for training and 500 for validation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CSAIL Places&lt;/strong&gt;
This dataset is more general and has a wide variety of scenes. It has approximately 20K examples
(2K validation), with annotations, and 100 classes. The CSAIL places dataset will give us an opportunity
to compare our results with work published that tested with more popular datasets like
MSCOCO [4].&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mask R-CNN Architecture&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bhavesh00.github.io/img/arch_mask.png&#34; alt=&#34;Mask R-CNN Architecture&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
