<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ashwani Khemani on Ashwani Khemani</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ashwani Khemani on Ashwani Khemani</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Time for a new beginning !!</title>
      <link>/post/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 20:23:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few days ago I read the following tweet somewhere on the internet !!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;When you’ve written the same code 3 times, write a function&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;When you’ve given the same in-person advice 3 times, write a blog post&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; David Robinson (@drob) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/drob/status/928447584712253440?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;November 9, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to relate it to my real life experience and it definitely did make a lot of sense. I have seen myself sometimes repeating and sharing the same advice with my friends and colleagues. So, I decided to start my own blog to share my learnings and experiences with everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoy reading and have become an avid reader (I would have been surprised if someone said that about me a couple of years ago).
I love to read about a lot of varied topics and yes anything related to the computers (we go long way back) and the technology. Currently, I am more occupied with reading academic texts and papers about topics of my interests and I would love to share anything I find interesting in them. Apart from reading, I really enjoy sharing my knowledge with people which is the main motivation behind this blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talking to people who are new to the field or are nervous because of the initial experience with something and helping them is something I have always cherished. &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Success is not counted by how high you have climbed but by how many people you brought with you&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/strong&gt;And I try to stand by this each and every day of my life. I do sometimes digress to philosophy even when I try very hard not to, I promise I would avoid it in the future posts :) But, coming back to the purpose of this blog and the interests that I would like to talk about here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find currently find the areas of &lt;em&gt;machine learning and distributed systems&lt;/em&gt; very fascinating. I would love to share my perspective about different concepts and try to make topics in those areas more interesting and understandable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently read an article which talked about why &lt;em&gt;deep learning&lt;/em&gt;, I apologize for the jargon. Let&amp;rsquo;s for now not focus on what does it mean as it&amp;rsquo;s not that important at the moment. The article said that the fact that deep learning is hyped is itself hyped. I agree with it as people are trying to make use of buzzwords to gain traction and there is nothing wrong with that. My point is, yes, it may be hyped, but what differentiates a genuine enthusiast and person who wants to make use of any form of science and technology is not how much hype one can create, it&amp;rsquo;s about how much impact one can have with their creation over the world and its population. This is the sole reason behind my curiosity about machine learning and distributed systems. I think they are very useful and if people try to make use of them to solve real-world problems, the opportunities are endless !!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I might sometimes write about some non-technical topics also, but yes I would try to keep them separate. I have found the internet and online communities very useful for the knowledge I have gained in my life. &lt;strong&gt;This is my way to give something back to it !!&lt;/strong&gt; I hope this blog would be useful for everyone and I would love to hear your comments and feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned !!!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Empirical Investigation into Large-Scale Devops Pipeline programs</title>
      <link>/project/pa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/pa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Investigated many Devops pipeline programs and obtained statistical data that describe content and patterns in Devops
pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Java, Jenkins, GitHub&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source Code available &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ashwanikhemani/PipelineAnalyzer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conditional Random Field for optical character recognition (OCR)</title>
      <link>/project/crf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/crf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed and developed parallel optimization algorithm based on the LBFGS solver provided by PETSc,
leveraging its parallel primitives and testing the scalability on cluster&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented stochastic gradient solvers (SGD and ADAM), and tested their efficiency in comparison with LBFGS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source Code available &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ashwanikhemani/ConvexOptimization&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevOps Orchestration to simulate end to end DevOps workflow at an enterprise level</title>
      <link>/project/do/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/do/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created a DevOps application workflow for automatically building and analyzing software applications statically as part of
the workflow to obtain information about relationships among components of these applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Java, Jenkins, Gitlab, GitHub&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source Code available &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ashwanikhemani/DevOpsOrchester&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instance Segmentation using Convolutional Neural Networks</title>
      <link>/project/maskrcnn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/maskrcnn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Mask R-CNN (Regional Convolutional Neural Network) can be used in instance
segmentation, and has been quite sucessful when compared with other architectures
for the same task. In this project we look at its performance on two
well known datasets, cityscapes and CSAIL Places, and try to see the impact of
modifying hyperparameters and using different network architectures in the backbone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Summary of the Problem
Instance Segmentation is the combination of three other tasks making it very difficult. Those three
tasks are Image Classification, Object Detection, and Semantic Segmentation. See Figure 1 for an
overview of the task.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Instance Segmentation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Classification, being the most studied of the three, is a task where you are given an image
and the goal is to classify it. Examples of such studies are those done on the MNIST dataset [1].
In MNIST, the task is to classify handwritten digits given only an image of the digit. Some of the
most successful approaches involve CNN architectures, like VGG, GoogleLeNet, ResNet, and many
others.
Object Detection has the same domain, but the goal is to find all instances of an object and find the
smallest bounding box around the object. One way to structure this as a machine learning task is
to formulate it as a Regression problem, where the bounding box is defined by a set of coordinates.
This is done in our Mask R-CNN implementation and its immediate predecessor, Faster R-CNN [2].
The goal of Semantic Segmentation is to classify each pixel, effectively segmenting an image into its
semantic components. This was a difficult task because there was no obvious way to generate predictions
for each pixel, without feeding the whole image multiple times through a traditional CNN
classification network, and this would make the problem intractable. One well known solution to
this is to use a Fully Convolutional Network (FCN), which would have an Encoder/Decoder structure
by first using Convolution Layers and Pooling&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cityscapes&lt;/strong&gt;
Cityscapes has data from street scenes, so an application of a network trained on this dataset is
autonomous vehicles. The dataset has approximately 5,000 examples and 30 classes with fine grain
annotations. We used about 3,500 for training and 500 for validation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CSAIL Places&lt;/strong&gt;
This dataset is more general and has a wide variety of scenes. It has approximately 20K examples
(2K validation), with annotations, and 100 classes. The CSAIL places dataset will give us an opportunity
to compare our results with work published that tested with more popular datasets like
MSCOCO [4].&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mask R-CNN Architecture&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/arch_mask.png&#34; alt=&#34;Mask R-CNN Architecture&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monte-Carlo simulation with OctaPi cloud</title>
      <link>/project/mcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/mcs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Performed Monte-Carlo simulation for evaluation of stock purchase decisions that runs on Spark and deployed on
private OctaPi cloud using Kubernetes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Java, Spark, Docker, K8s&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source Code available &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ashwanikhemani/OctaPi--MonteCarloTradingSimulator&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parallelization of software testing using Hadoop Map-Reduce model and OctaPi Cluster</title>
      <link>/project/st/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/st/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Built and designed an OctaPi cloud cluster of Raspberry PI devices to run a Hadoop map/reduce application to make
software testing process parallel and efficient
Automated deploying, scaling, and operating application containers on Raspberry Pi using Kubernetes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Java, Hadoop, Docker, K8s&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source Code available &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ashwanikhemani/OctaPi-HadoopMR&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentiment Analysis of Twitter Corpus</title>
      <link>/project/sm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/sm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conducted comparative study of Machine Learning and Deep Learning models for Sentiment Analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed deep learning models to achieve state of the art performance on complex task such as sentiment analysis
on twitter dataset&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source Code available &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ashwanikhemani/TwitterSentimentAnalysis&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Static Code Analyzer to find most common bugs in Open Source Projects</title>
      <link>/project/sca/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/sca/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Obtained information about program entities that were modified because of fixes to specific bugs/issues and found useful
pattern amongst them using static code analysis tool like Understand&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Python, GitHub, Understand&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source Code available &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ashwanikhemani/StaticCodeAnalyzer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structured Output Prediction using Conditional Random Fields</title>
      <link>/project/crf_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/crf_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developed a conditional random field model for Optical Character Recognition (OCR), with emphasis on inference
and performance test&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Performed benchmarking by comparing CRF with multi-class linear SVM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source Code available &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ashwanikhemani/CRF&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
