<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Ashwani Khemani</title>
    <link>https://bhavesh00.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Ashwani Khemani</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://bhavesh00.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>That aha moment!!</title>
      <link>https://bhavesh00.github.io/post/aha_moment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 23:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhavesh00.github.io/post/aha_moment/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s has been a long time since I last posted an article not related to a coursework at UIC. But, I would like to change this trend and would try to post about my learnings and experiences more often from now on.
There are few moments in life where a person discovers something and things start making some sort of sense after that.It is has been two years since I joined graduate school at University of Illinois at Chicago to pursue my Masters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Governments Help People Succeed!!</title>
      <link>https://bhavesh00.github.io/post/good_gov/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 17:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhavesh00.github.io/post/good_gov/</guid>
      <description>Link to the visualization : Good Governments Help People Succeed
 &amp;ldquo;The care of human life and happiness, and not their destruction, is the first and only object of good government.&amp;rdquo; - Thomas Jefferson
 Purpose of Visualization
How can we measure the success of a government and what criteria should be used to label a government as &amp;ldquo;good government&amp;rdquo; ?
Gross Domestic Product (GDP) is commonly used as a metric to compare two countries and their government.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Every Breath You Take !!</title>
      <link>https://bhavesh00.github.io/post/evlproject2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 13:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhavesh00.github.io/post/evlproject2/</guid>
      <description>This is the second project for the CS 424 Visualization and Visual Analytics class at UIC. It consists in various visualizations and interactive plots in a web application created using the Shiny library for R. The visualizations are about the Air Quality dataset by County in the United States and Italy, concentrating on the yearly, daily and hourly data.
You can access the application from here .
You can learn more about the application here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just Breathe Group - Interesting Things !!</title>
      <link>https://bhavesh00.github.io/post/project1group/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 17:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhavesh00.github.io/post/project1group/</guid>
      <description>Group:
 Ashwani Khemani Abhishek Vasudevan Varsha Jayaraman  Abhishek solution:
 The UI is easy to navigate and it&amp;rsquo;s easy to follow things on the screen. The colors are pleasing and they work for the color blind people. The different charts had error messages for the case when no data was found for given user input.  Ashwani solution:
 The overall work done by him was good. He has organized the different visualizations properly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just Breathe - Code !!</title>
      <link>https://bhavesh00.github.io/post/evlproject1code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 19:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhavesh00.github.io/post/evlproject1code/</guid>
      <description>The code for the project can be found here .
The data needed for the project is available in the root folder and the map data is available in the map folder of the project.
The instructions to run the code:
 Online : The project can be run through this link
 Offline : To run the project in the local environment , please follow the below instructions.
 Download the R-language from the R-website</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just Breathe - Data!!</title>
      <link>https://bhavesh00.github.io/post/evlproject1data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 19:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhavesh00.github.io/post/evlproject1data/</guid>
      <description>The page contains information about the data used in the Just Breathe project. The data was downloaded from the EPA website.
The link to download the data is here
The files for annual summary of data for counties was downloaded from years 1980-2018.
The files were then extracted and imported using R Studio to create visualization as described in the project</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just Breathe --Findings !!</title>
      <link>https://bhavesh00.github.io/post/evlproject1findings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 19:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhavesh00.github.io/post/evlproject1findings/</guid>
      <description>Project Link
Interesting things which were found about the data using the application.
The findings are given below for the Cook county of Illinois.
 Amongst the pollutants, SO2 pollutant has shown a relatively downward trend over the last 25 years with some exceptions in certain years. PM2.5 pollutant has shown a relatively upward trend over the last 25 years with some exceptions in certain years. CO , Carbon monozide emission has been neglible over the last 20 years  These trends show that there has been an effor to reduce harmful emissions but at the same time there are still emissions that need to be controlled to bring them under permissible range.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The X-Rite Color Challenge and Hue Test !!</title>
      <link>https://bhavesh00.github.io/post/color_test/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 12:54:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhavesh00.github.io/post/color_test/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EVL Weather Application !!</title>
      <link>https://bhavesh00.github.io/post/evl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 19:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhavesh00.github.io/post/evl/</guid>
      <description>Here is the link to the website deployed using shinny apps account
EVL Weather</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weather Updates !!</title>
      <link>https://bhavesh00.github.io/post/weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 19:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhavesh00.github.io/post/weather/</guid>
      <description>I get my weather updates from the weather channel !!! I usually visit weather channel because it provides the most accurate and up to date weather updates. It shows hourly, daily and weekly weather forecast in an organized manner. The website and phone application are easy to navigate and to use. I highly recommend the application to everyone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time for a new beginning !!</title>
      <link>https://bhavesh00.github.io/post/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 20:23:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhavesh00.github.io/post/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago I read the following tweet somewhere on the internet !!
When you’ve written the same code 3 times, write a function
When you’ve given the same in-person advice 3 times, write a blog post
&amp;mdash; David Robinson (@drob) November 9, 2017 
I tried to relate it to my real life experience and it definitely did make a lot of sense. I have seen myself sometimes repeating and sharing the same advice with my friends and colleagues.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>